[
    {
        "passage": [
            "It is very important to have healthy teeth. Good teeth help us to chew our food. They also help us to look nice. How does a tooth go bad? The decay begins in a little crack in the enamel covering the tooth. This happens after germs and bits of food have collected there. Then the decay slowly spreads inside the tooth. Eventually, poison goes into the blood, and we may feel quite ill.",
            "How can we keep our teeth healthy? Firstly, we ought to visit our dentist twice a year. He can fill the small holes in our teeth before they destroy the teeth. He can examine our teeth to check that they are growing in the right way. Unfortunately, many people wait until they have a toothache before they see a dentist. Secondly, we should brush our teeth with a toothbrush and fluoride toothpaste at least twice a day - once after breakfast and once before we go to bed. We can also use wooden toothpicks to clean between our teeth after a meal. Thirdly, we should eat food that is good for our teeth and our body: milk, cheese, fish, brown bread, potatoes, red rice, raw vegetables, and fresh fruit. Chocolates, sweets, biscuits, and cakes are bad, especially when we eat them between meals. They are harmful because they stick to our teeth and cause decay."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "When there is a little crack in the enamel covering the tooth, our teeth ___",
                "A": "become hard",
                "B": "make us feel quite good",
                "C": "begin to decay",
                "D": "become healthy",
                "answer": "begin to decay"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'spreads' mean?",
                "A": "grows",
                "B": "reduces",
                "C": "sends",
                "D": "collects",
                "answer": "grows"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'Eventually” mean?",
                "A": "Firstly",
                "B": "Slowly",
                "C": "Lastly",
                "D": "Moreover",
                "answer": "Lastly"
            },
            {
                "question": "How often should we visit the dentist?",
                "A": "twice a month",
                "B": "twice a week",
                "C": "twice a year",
                "D": "every year",
                "answer": "twice a year"
            },
            {
                "question": "A lot of people do not visit a dentist until______",
                "A": "they have a toothache",
                "B": "they use wooden toothpicks",
                "C": "they have brushed their teeth",
                "D": "their teeth grow properly",
                "answer": "they have a toothache"
            },
            {
                "question": "When do we need to brush the teeth?",
                "A": "Before the breakfast and after the meal",
                "B": "Before breakfast and before the meal",
                "C": "After the breakfast and before going to bed",
                "D": "Before the meals and before going to bed",
                "answer": "After the breakfast and before going to bed"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'wooden' mean?",
                "A": "made of wood",
                "B": "made of steel",
                "C": "made of iron",
                "D": "made of nylon",
                "answer": "made of wood"
            },
            {
                "question": "What may be beneficial to our teeth?",
                "A": "Ice-cream",
                "B": "vegetables and fruits",
                "C": "caffeine",
                "D": "tea",
                "answer": "vegetables and fruits"
            },
            {
                "question": "What may be most harmful to our teeth?",
                "A": "red rice",
                "B": "raw vegetables",
                "C": "fresh fruit",
                "D": "sweet things",
                "answer": "sweet things"
            },
            {
                "question": "How many pieces of advice are there to keep our teeth healthy",
                "A": "1",
                "B": "2",
                "C": "3",
                "D": "4",
                "answer": "3"
            },
            {
                "question": "The best title for the passage would be_____",
                "A": "How to keep our teeth healthy",
                "B": "How to make our teeth nicer",
                "C": "How to dean our teeth",
                "D": "How to keep our teeth ever white",
                "answer": "How to keep our teeth healthy"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "Christopher Columbus was born in Genoa, Italy in 1451. While spending most of his early years at sea, Columbus began to believe that he could find a shortcut to the Indies by sailing west across the Atlantic Ocean. Unfortunately, the King of Portugal refused to finance such a trip, and Columbus was forced to present his idea to the King and Queen of Spain. In 1492, King Ferdinand and Queen Isabella agreed to pay for his trip. They gave him a crew and three ships, the Nina, Pinta and Santa Maria. Columbus sailed aboard the Santa Maria.",
            "The trip was long and hard. Many sailors grew restless and wanted to turn around. After two months at sea, land was finally sighted. The ships docked on the island of Hispaniola. Columbus named the native people he saw 'Indians', because he believed he had found the shortcut he was looking for. In reality, Columbus found North America, a brand new continent at that time.",
            "Columbus, however, couldn’t be convinced. He died with the belief he had found the shortcut to the Indies. Soon, however, other explorers and nations understood the importance of his discoveries, Columbus' discoveries set the stage for the Age of Exploration, one of the most fascinating and exciting times in the world history."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Where was Christopher Columbus born?",
                "A": "The New World",
                "B": "Portugal",
                "C": "Spain",
                "D": "Italy",
                "answer": "Italy"
            },
            {
                "question": "Columbus believed he could find a shortcut to the",
                "A": "America",
                "B": "Indies",
                "C": "Spain",
                "D": "Atlantic Ocean",
                "answer": "Indies"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'shortcut' mean?",
                "A": "trip",
                "B": "short way",
                "C": "journey",
                "D": "voyage",
                "answer": "short way"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'finance' mean?",
                "A": "pay for",
                "B": "agree",
                "C": "share",
                "D": "present",
                "answer": "pay for"
            },
            {
                "question": "Columbus set sail",
                "A": "In 1451",
                "B": "In 1492",
                "C": "Before 1451",
                "D": "Before 1492",
                "answer": "In 1492"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'crew' mean?",
                "A": "team",
                "B": "alone",
                "C": "money",
                "D": "gun",
                "answer": "team"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following was NOT one of his ships?",
                "A": "Nina",
                "B": "Isabella",
                "C": "Pinta",
                "D": "Santa Maria",
                "answer": "Isabella"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which is NOT true?",
                "A": "Columbus was born in Italy",
                "B": "Columbus received three ships and a crew from the King and Queen of Spain.",
                "C": "Columbus found a shortcut to the Indies",
                "D": "The journey across the Atlantic took two months.",
                "answer": "Columbus found a shortcut to the Indies"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'restless' mean?",
                "A": "without resting",
                "B": "without working",
                "C": "without eating",
                "D": "without sailing",
                "answer": "without resting"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'reality' mean?",
                "A": "though",
                "B": "tum",
                "C": "order",
                "D": "fact",
                "answer": "fact"
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Columbus name the native people he saw?",
                "A": "King Ferdinand",
                "B": "Queen Isabella",
                "C": "Christopher Columbus",
                "D": "The Indians",
                "answer": "Christopher Columbus"
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Columbus name the native people he saw?",
                "A": "Indies",
                "B": "Indians",
                "C": "Indi",
                "D": "American",
                "answer": "Indians"
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Columbus actually find?",
                "A": "The Indies",
                "B": "North America",
                "C": "Atlantic Ocean",
                "D": "Genoa",
                "answer": "North America"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "Green is a beautiful color in nature, the grass that you walk on is green and the leaves that you see on trees are usually green. Most of the plants that you see are green, too! Frogs are green and many grasshoppers are green, too. Turtles are different shades of green.",
            "Did you know that you can make green paint with blue and yellow? Because you can make green by mixing two primary colors, it is called a secondary color. Green is also the name used to describe the movement to make products that do not harm the Earth. Green products are often those made from recycled materials or those that are safe to throw out in the trash."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which of the following might be an example of a green product?",
                "A": "a plastic bottle that can be recycled",
                "B": "a big truck",
                "C": "a frog",
                "D": "a plastic bottle that cannot be recycled",
                "answer": "a plastic bottle that can be recycled"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following might not be an example of green in nature?",
                "A": "the grass",
                "B": "the plant",
                "C": "the leaf",
                "D": "the bike",
                "answer": "the bike"
            },
            {
                "question": "According to the passage, which is NOT given as an example of green?",
                "A": "A mushroom",
                "B": "A frog",
                "C": "A grasshopper",
                "D": "A leaf",
                "answer": "A mushroom"
            },
            {
                "question": "Turtles are___",
                "A": "different shades of green",
                "B": "green products",
                "C": "not found in nature",
                "D": "not green",
                "answer": "different shades of green"
            },
            {
                "question": "Green paint can be created by mixing___",
                "A": "yellow and red",
                "B": "yellow and blue",
                "C": "yellow and purple",
                "D": "yellow and brown",
                "answer": "yellow and blue"
            },
            {
                "question": "Green is called___ by mixing two primary colors.",
                "A": "primary color",
                "B": "a type of kite",
                "C": "a secondary color",
                "D": "a kind of trash",
                "answer": "a secondary color"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'primary' mean?",
                "A": "new",
                "B": "unimportant",
                "C": "private",
                "D": "basic",
                "answer": "basic"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the word 'movement' closest in meaning to?",
                "A": "journey",
                "B": "trip",
                "C": "visit",
                "D": "action",
                "answer": "action"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is a green product?",
                "A": "One that does not harm the Earth",
                "B": "One that is fun",
                "C": "One that is mixed together",
                "D": "One that is made from grass",
                "answer": "One that does not harm the Earth"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which can be the best title for the passage?",
                "A": "Green color",
                "B": "Green animals",
                "C": "Green plants",
                "D": "the Earth",
                "answer": "Green color"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "Alexander Graham Bell was born in Edinburgh, Scotland on March 3, 1847. When he was only eleven years old, he invented a machine that could clean wheat. Graham studied anatomy and physiology at the University of London, but moved with his family to Quebec, Canada in 1870.",
            "Bell soon moved to Boston, Massachusetts. In 1871, he began working with deaf people and published the system of Visible Hearing that was developed by his father. Visible Hearing illustrates how the tongue, lips, and throat are used to produce vocal sounds. In 1872, Bell founded a school for the deaf which soon became part of Boston University.",
            "Alexander Graham Bell is best known for his invention of the telephone. While trying to discover the secret of transmitting multiple messages on a single wire, Bell heard the sound of a plucked string along some of the electrical wires. One of Bell’s assistants, Thomas A. Watson, was trying to reactivate a telephone transmitter. After hearing the sound, Bell believed he could send the sound of a human voice over the wire. After receiving a patent on March 7, 1876 for transmitting sound along a single wire, he successfully transmitted human speech on March 10th. Bell’s telephone patent was one of the most valuable patents ever granted. He started the Bell Telephone Company in 1877.",
            "Alexander Graham Bell died on August 2, 1922. On the day of his burial, in honor of Bell, all telephone services in the United States were stopped for one minute."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Where was Alexander Graham Bell born?",
                "A": "England",
                "B": "Quebec",
                "C": "Scotland",
                "D": "Boston",
                "answer": "Scotland"
            },
            {
                "question": "When did he invent the machine that could clean wheat?",
                "A": "In 1947",
                "B": "In 1958",
                "C": "In 1870",
                "D": "In 1871",
                "answer": "In 1958"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who developed the system of Visible Hearing?",
                "A": "Himself",
                "B": "His workmate",
                "C": "His father",
                "D": "The deaf",
                "answer": "His father"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'illustrates' mean?",
                "A": "describes",
                "B": "draws",
                "C": "moves",
                "D": "listens",
                "answer": "describes"
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Alexander Graham Bell do in 1872?",
                "A": "He invented a machine for cleaning wheat.",
                "B": "He founded a school for deaf people",
                "C": "He invented the telephone",
                "D": "He studied at the University of London",
                "answer": "He founded a school for deaf people"
            },
            {
                "question": "What happened FIRST?",
                "A": "Bell invented the telephone",
                "B": "Bell moved to Canada",
                "C": "Bell published the Visible Hearing system",
                "D": "Bell moved to Massachusetts",
                "answer": "Bell moved to Canada"
            },
            {
                "question": "Bell was most famous for the invention of_______",
                "A": "photograph",
                "B": "telephone",
                "C": "wire",
                "D": "electricity",
                "answer": "telephone"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was Thomas A. Watson?",
                "A": "Bell's assistant",
                "B": "Bell's cousin",
                "C": "Bell's son",
                "D": "Bell's friend",
                "answer": "Bell's assistant"
            },
            {
                "question": "What was Thomas doing when Alexander heard the sound of a plucked string along some of the electrical wires?",
                "A": "Transmitting multiple messages over a single wire",
                "B": "Transmitting the human voice over a single wire",
                "C": "Starting the Bell Telephone Company",
                "D": "Reactivating a telephone transmitter",
                "answer": "Reactivating a telephone transmitter"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'transmitted' mean?",
                "A": "blocked by stopping",
                "B": "sent out",
                "C": "made larger",
                "D": "disturbed",
                "answer": "sent out"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word 'granted' mean?",
                "A": "welcomed",
                "B": "issued",
                "C": "loved",
                "D": "started",
                "answer": "issued"
            },
            {
                "question": "What happened in 1877?",
                "A": "He started the Bell Telephone Company",
                "B": "He closed the Bell Telephone Company.",
                "C": "He left the Bell Telephone Company.",
                "D": "He hired the Bell Telephone Company.",
                "answer": "He started the Bell Telephone Company"
            },
            {
                "question": "He died at the age of_____",
                "A": "73",
                "B": "75",
                "C": "77",
                "D": "79",
                "answer": "75"
            },
            {
                "question": "What happened on the day of his burial?",
                "A": "All telephone services in the world were stopped.",
                "B": "All telephone services in the US were stopped for one hour.",
                "C": "All telephone services in the world were stopped for sixty seconds.",
                "D": "All telephone services in the US were stopped for sixty seconds",
                "answer": "All telephone services in the US were stopped for sixty seconds"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which can be the best title for the passage?",
                "A": "Alexander Graham Bell's life and inventions",
                "B": "Alexander Graham Bell's inventions",
                "C": "The best inventor of all time",
                "D": "Alexander Graham Bell's experiments",
                "answer": "Alexander Graham Bell's life and inventions"
            }
        ]
    }
]